<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anirban Chatterjee</title>
    <link>http://anirbanchatterjee.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anirban Chatterjee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="http://anirbanchatterjee.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://anirbanchatterjee.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anirbanchatterjee.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a post-doc at CEA Saclay, where I use machine learning / deep learning methods to analyze processes that happen at the atomic scale 🔬 in metals: defects formation, thermally activated process, phase transformations, materials evolution in environment, ... For this, I currently develop efficient atomic descriptors and machine-learning (ML) force-fields, together with Mihai-Cosmin Marinica and Alexandra M. Goryaeva.
I intensively use massively parallel computational methods such as molecular dynamics to study solid state physics problems at different scales, using both classical and ML-based methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>http://anirbanchatterjee.com/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anirbanchatterjee.com/blog/</guid>
      <description>Hey</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://anirbanchatterjee.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://anirbanchatterjee.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Papers Neighbors Map: an Efficient Atomic Descriptor for Structural Analysis Arnaud Allera, Alexandra M. Goryaeva, Paul Lafourcade, Jean-Bernard Maillet, Mihai-Cosmin Marinica arXiv:2307.00978 &amp;mdash; Github Robust crystal structure identification at extreme conditions using a density-independent spectral descriptor and supervised learning Paul Lafourcade, Jean-Bernard Maillet, Christophe Denoual, Eléonore Duval, Arnaud Allera, Alexandra M. Goryaeva, Mihai-Cosmin Marinica. arXiv:2307.01560 Carbon-induced strengthening of bcc iron at the atomic scale Arnaud Allera, Fabienne Ribeiro, Michel Perez, and David Rodney.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
